# **David Emerson**

# Web Developer

Full-stack web developer who loves building quick and efficient solutions. My 12 years of sales and client service experience have made me skilled at identifying project needs and applying the appropriate technologies to meet them. As a recent boot camp graduate, I'm eager to reapply these existing skills to a new market.

## **Personal Info**

### Address

16205 W 124th Cir Olathe, KS 66062

### **Phone**

913-568-3060

#### E-mail

david@david-emerson.com

### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/djemerson/

### Portfolio & Github

david-emerson.com github.com/davidjemerson

### Skills

Languages & Frameworks

**Javascript** 

**j**Query

React

mySQL and noSQL (Mongo)

Node.js and npm

Next.is

**PHP** 

HTML

**CSS** 

Systems/Software

WordPress

Photoshop

Visual Studio Code

Soft Skills

Project Management Creative Problem Solving Effective Collaboration

## **Experience**

## **Director of Sales and Customer Service**

TradeNet Publishing

Feb 2016 - Aug 2018

- Trained and supervised a staff of 15 Customer Service professionals
- Engaged with top distributors to learn about their clients' needs and built product solutions to meet them
- Organized and refined co-marketing strategies with clients to achieve growth in new products and markets

# **Director of Business Development**

Allen Press

May 2012 - Feb 2016

- Identified new clients for publication printing, including startups
- Grew publications business through same client sales of additional titles and ancillary pieces
- Maintained year over year growth in assigned territory despite a declining market

## **Account Manager**

Allen Press

Oct 2006 - May 2012

- Acted as primary point of contact for over 65 client accounts
- Oversaw production of over 150 print projects annually, coordinating inter-departmental production efforts to ensure on time delivery

## **Education**

## **University of Kansas**

Full-Stack Coding Boot Camp

Jan 2018 - July 2018

- Primarily focused on honing my Javascript and back-end development skills
- Created assigned projects on a weekly basis, ranging from simple front-end layouts to full-stack applications
- Worked within groups to concept and build larger projects

# Pittsburg State University

**BST** in Commercial Graphics

Sep 2000 - May 2004

Focus on desktop publishing, web design, and photography